# Marat Abdulin

Software Engineer

I'm a skilled software engineer with more than 12 years of experience in web development. During this time I've been working with a variety of technologies and projects. My knowledge covers a broad range of modern full-stack development. I'm proficient in both front-end and back-end technologies.

I'm fond of solving performance issues, working on complex problems and searching for the best solutions that are suitable for both tech and business.



# Skills

### **JavaScript**

React, Preact, Vue React env libraries Webpack, Parcel Jest, Ava, Mocha, Chai, Sinon

#### Ruby

Ruby on Rails, Hanami

#### **Databases**

PostgreSQL, MySQL Redis, MongoDB

#### **NodeJS**

Express, Fastify, Nuxt Bolt, Telegraf Sequilize, Mongoose

### Other

Debugging
Front-end performance
HTML5, CSS3
Mentoring
Team Leading

## Contacts

@ marat@esender.me

n esender

in <u>esender</u> **∡** @esender

**S** esender.me

# Languages

English / B1 Russian / native Tatar / native

# Work experience

## Earnest Inc.

Software Engineer (VanillaJS, Preact, Webpack, Jira, Optimizely, Wordpress)

- Improved page speed performance
- Improved build size and coding experience using webpack

## Student Loan Hero Inc.

Front-end Engineer (React, VanillaJS, Webpack, Jira, Wordpress, CodeShip)

- Optimized bundle size, page loading speed, and performance
- Improved code quality, coding experience using webpack

January 2019 — Present Remote

March 2018 — January 2019 Remote

## **Runtime LLC**

Front-end Engineer (React, Webpack, Jira, Gemini, Rspec, GitLab CI)

March 2016 — March 2018 Kazan, Russia

- Improved build and render performance
- Covered project by unit and screenshot tests

## Racoons Group LLC

Full-Stack Engineer (Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, Backbone, Express)

October 2012 — December 2015 Kazan, Russia

- Grew up to team leader
- Worked on important projects

Freelance
Web Developer (HTML & CSS, Joomla, PHPShop, jQuery)

2008 — October 2012 Kazan, Russia

September 2007 – July 2011

# Education

# Kazan National Research Technical University named after A.N.Tupolev

Institute of radio-engineering and telecommunications

Bachelor of Engineering and Technology